GLOBAL PRODUCT MARKETING MANAGER

Experience

Global Product Marketing Manager

January 2015 to January 2018 Veeam i $^1\!\!/_{\!\!4}$ Omaha , NE

- Global product management ownership for multiple new product development projects including market specifications, long-range plans, and driving the organization's focus on market/customer specific insights and needs Product Owner for new products in multiple channels for over \$35M of new business Cross-culturally gather business to business voice of the customer globally on new projects by vertical interviewing Develop Global Marketing/Sales Plans including target markets and positioning strategy for 5-year strategic global plan Assessed current product portfolios and discussed with Director of Sales and Marketing to develop product road maps and manage the product life cycle.
- Championed market studies, business cases and marketing/sales plans resulting in new business cases and investment requests Worked with
 Marketing Communications to develop marketing high quality marketing content for upcoming and ongoing product lunch and trade shows
 Global and regional leadership on launch for new product introductions Work with regional pricing teams in Americas, Europe, APAC and
 China to develop pricing strategy and alignment Train and mentor new Product Marketing Managers in Americas and Europe.

Product Marketing Manager

January 2011 to January 2015 Patra il/4 San Diego, CA

Hydrostatics Utilize voice of the customer and internal product experts to create product vision for new product developments including, market specifications, market and sales plan, overall portfolio plan including full life cycle management and phase out Develop input and market data for global hot spots Assess current product portfolios, develop product road maps and manage the product life cycle Champion market studies, competitive benchmarking, business cases and marketing/sales plans resulting in new business cases and investment requests.

Product Planning, Marketing Manager January 2008 to January 2011 Patra il/4 Topeka, KS

- Lead new product launch process while transitioning manufacturing locations, starting from concept development through commercial launch for over 400 models in 3 years Managed multiple direct reports locally and internationally Worked directly with Brand Marketing and Market Communications teams in developing marketing collateral and messaging for Electrolux Brand Launch for Fabric Care Developed 5-year strategic plan for \$600+M USD business including P&L responsibility Won approval for over \$70 Million of new product development projects Worked in global product development teams with representatives from multiple countries including; Italy, Brazil and Mexico Constructed market specifications for new models using consumer insight, market trends and channel strategy Benchmarked market conditions, strategy, pricing, generational planning, and competitive analysis Facilitated growth of market, profitability and sales, globally Developed sales strategies and conducted training on all new products and features Worked globally with consumer insight to identify consumer needs locally Revamped all training materials to focus on consumer insight driven features and benefits versus only technology Worked directly with R&D, Sales, Brand Teams, Finance, Operations, and Purchasing on new products, cost out opportunities, and improvements in factory efficiencies Worked with regulatory agencies such as Department of Energy, AHAM, UL, Intertek, CSA, NSF, Energy Star, and CEE Assisted in orchestrating the successful relocation and launch of a new manufacturing facility in Mexico including extensive international travel.
- Lead product line development of messaging for point of sale materials, brochures and website updates for new products Electrolux Major Appliances.

Product Marketing Manager January 2007 to January 2008

Organized New Model Launches, costing, and timing of critical components for marketing, advertising and industrialization of new products
Manage Channel Strategy and model lineup Worked with quality to develop aesthetic specifications and fit, feel and finish requirements that
exceeds customer expectations Developed specifications for new products based off market conditions, sales requirements, and consumer
research Organized sales meetings and technical reviews with national and local accounts Lead efforts on competitive analysis and
competitive tear-downs.

Education

 $A.A: Business\ Administration\ ,\ December\ 2002\ DMACC\ Community\ College\ i'/4\ City\ ,\ State\ Business\ Administration\ B.S.B.A: Business\ Management\ and\ Marketing\ ,\ August\ 2006\ Drake\ University\ i'/4\ City\ ,\ State\ Business\ Management\ and\ Marketing\ Certified\ Scrum\ Product\ Owner\ (CSPO)\ ,\ Agile42: July\ 2017$

Summary

Passionate Global Product Marketing Manager with over 11 years of product management experience developing multiple technology and consumer products in B2B and B2C markets.

Languages

English: Native language

Highlights

- NPD Database, Tragline
- MS Excel, Word, PowerPoint
- Lotus Notes
- Salesforce
- AutoCAD (Basic)
- Windows
- SAP
- SharePoint

Skills

advertising, Agile, AutoCAD, Basic, benchmarking, benefits, Brand Marketing, brochures, competitive, competitive analysis, concept development, content, costing, Database, driving, English, features, Finance, focus, full life cycle, Global Marketing, leadership, Lotus Notes, Director, market trends, marketing, Market, marketing collateral, Marketing Communications, marketing/sales, market and sales, materials, meetings, mentor, messaging, MS Excel, PowerPoint, SharePoint, Windows, Word, NSF, new product development, positioning, pricing strategy, product development, develop product, product management, Product Marketing, Purchasing, quality, research, Sales, Sales Plans, SAP, Scrum, Strategy, strategic, tear, trade shows, training materials, vision, website